mobile email website 1 (949) 542-9693 matthewhogeboom@gmail.com

matthogeboom.com

#### Introduction

My name is Matt. I am a designer currently living in Laguna Niguel California. I have 18 years of experience designing and building websites and interactive applications. A former Senior Designer at Newsday.com in NY, I have been working as a freelance designer and contractor for electricbricks.net, designing and building responsive websites. I have previously worked in a variety of different environments from corporations to boutique agencies. I have excelled at delivering award-winning projects and I enjoy the pace of creative, collaborative environments.

# Professional Experience

#### **Electric Bricks**

Web Designer

2018 - Present

Web design and development. Leverage WordPress and HTML/CSS for the development of responsive websites

#### Newsday LLC

Lead Designer

September 2008 - December 2017

Worked with award-winning team of developers on web projects as well as mobile apps. Designed and developed web and mobile applications, managed projects and coordinated with department teams to deliver projects accurately and on schedule. Managed third-party applications, site trouble-shooting and ensuring cross browser compatibility for high-traffic news industry.

#### Zero Gravity

Web Designer

December 2007 - August 2008

Designed and managed projects from concept through completion. Managed Flash enhanced websites. Designed and developed dynamic websites using HTML, CSS, AJAX, jQuery and PHP. Coordinated with clients on web content and website management with MODX.

### LKGS Interactive

Senior Designer

May 2004 - September 2007

Brand development. Logo, print and website design. Dynamic data-driven website development and email campaigns using HTML, PHP and FLASH. Created and managed web projects with remote staff from conception through completion.

## Skills

PC/Mac Platforms
UI Design
Illustration
Branding Development
WordPress
HTML
CSS/SASS
Bootstrap

## Tools

Adobe Photoshop Adobe Illustrator Adobe XD Adobe Premiere Sketch WordPress VS Code

# **Education**

Hendrick's Institute of Technology Certificate of Interative Design 1999-2000

Stony Brook University Undergrad EGL 1996 - 1998

Suffolk County Community College Associates Degree 1994 - 1996

#### **Awards**

2010 - Emmy:

Alzheimer's: The love and the heart-break - Best interactive design

2013 BOLI

News12.com – Best website redesign

2014 Newsday Extra:

For outstanding effort, commitment to excellence

2015 Press Club of Long Island: Newsday.com – Best website redesign